#### Contact

firaskudsy@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/firaskudsy (LinkedIn) firaskudsy.github.io (Portfolio) firaskudsy.com (Portfolio)

### Top Skills

System Architecture Solution Architecture Problem Solving

Languages

Arabic

English

# Firas Kudsy

Lead Developer

Greater Toronto Area, Canada

## Summary

A full-stack developer with a passion for building great web applications, with over 20 years of proven software development skills and proficiency in the latest programming languages and web development frameworks technologies gained through years of successful implementations. Capable of carrying tasks independently or with minimal supervision. Solutions orientated, performing very well under pressure, achieving deadlines, and working within budgets.

# Experience

TD

Senior Full Stack Developer November 2018 - Present (5 years 10 months) Mississauga, Ontario, Canada

- Accomplished technical architecture design for multiple QE custom tools.
- Developed 10+ reporting services & web applications for Coverage, ROI, test executions, accessibility code, and environment downtime. The stack includes (Javascript, TypeScript, MS SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJs, React.js, Angular, Nginx)
- Developed multiple backend Rest API, services, and micro-services to integrate HP ALM, Jira, JTMF with QE Custom tools.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Lead web application migration to production on Azure.

Fitviser.com
Full Stack Developer
December 2016 - November 2018 (2 years)
Toronto, Canada Area

- Create innovative, interactive, and Scalable E-Commerce web applications. The stack includes ( JavaScript, TypeScript, Firebase, MongoDB, NodeJS, Loopback, Angular, Nginx, and Jenkins)
- Develop and Maintain User Dashboard Web Applications.

Page 1 of 3

- Develop and Maintain Hybrid E-Commerce Mobile Dashboard with Ionic Framework
- Take part in the technical architecture design process.

Ingenico Group - Contract
Terminal Software Customization
August 2016 - December 2016 (5 months)

Toronto, Canada Area

- Troubleshooting Terminals software fault
- Installing Terminals base software

Freelance Web Development
Full Stack Developer
January 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 7 months)
Beirut District, Lebanon

- Developed a Hybrid Mobile Apps for Restaurant Ordering, Delivery and tracking using ionic framework, AngularJS and Node js
- Built a custom mobile app for "Basmayah City" using ionic framework to enable app users to follow their monthly payments, remaining amounts and to provide the user with their nominated apartment address
- Developed a scheduling web application using Angular2 and Firebase to manage employees tasks and resources
- Developed a full Auditing system using VB.NET, DevExpress and SQL Server, including chart tables, chart of accounts, daily vouchers, statement of account, balance and a full set of reports
- Built a native Android app for daily transactions, used for posting users transactions to the backend REST API server
- Designed and Customized wordpress sites with modern responsive web UI standards

AL ITKAN ( Siemens agent )
Software Developer
June 2009 - December 2014 (5 years 7 months)
Baghdad, Iraq

- Developed a collaborative applications using VB.NET, SQL Server and DevExpress including HR, Stock management, travel Visa system and custom salary management
- Designed and Built wordpress sites with modern responsive web UI standards

- Analyzed business needs and planned methods to improve business process and performance using custom designed software
- Debugged and Resolved bugs in .NET applications to ensure optimal development environment
- Designed data structures and stored procedures, and tune existing stored procedures on SQL Server 2008

Arab Fund for Arts and Culture Software Developer June 2007 - May 2009 (2 years) Amman Governorate, Jordan

- Developed a Contacts dashboard system Microsoft Sharepoint
- Built a Custom data migration tool to collect and export filtered data to be imported later into a SharePoint Server
- Designed and Developed multiple business website using wordpress, HTML,
   Css, JavaScript and MySQL

AL ITKAN Communication ( Siemens agent )
Software Developer
August 2004 - May 2007 (2 years 10 months)
Baghdad, Iraq

- Developed a full Helpdesk application using VB.NET, SQL Server, and Crystal report to managing service requests, available technicians, time schedules, and resources
- Developed a Call center application using VB.NET, SQL Server, and Crystal report to record incoming client's requests, claims, and confirmation.

AL THAKIRA Integrated System's Software Developer December 2002 - July 2004 (1 year 8 months) Baghdad, Iraq

Developed an Archiving system to manage heritage documents records, tags, search keywords and scanned images

### Education

Baghdad University
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science